# **Nati Gebregorgis**

nati.g5684@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Portfolio | +966 559264431

#### **SUMMARY**

Full Stack Developer with experience in using Ruby on Rails on the back-end and React on the front-end. For the past two years, I've developed complex projects using React, JavaScript, & Ruby on Rails. Skilled with debugging and collaborating remotely. Seeking opportunities to utilize my skills and grow as a developer.

#### **SKILLS**

Front-End: JavaScript, React, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap.

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL.

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Mobile/Responsive Development, Chrome Dev Tools.

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

### Full Stack Web Developer

Jan 2022 - Present

Mastered intermediate and advanced topics in full-stack development (including Front-End Development, Rails, Git, and DS&A challenges) while building 15+ full-stack projects both independently and via pair-programming. Some of them are listed below:

- Space Travels This is a web application for a company that provides commercial and scientific
  space travel services. The application will allow users to book rockets and join selected space
  missions. All information is actual live data from the SpaceX API. Built with: JavaScript, HTML, React,
  Redux, & API.
- MovieSpace This web application is based on an external API. We selected an API that provides
  data about top-rated movies and then built a web app around it. The web app has two user
  interfaces. Built with: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Webpack & API.
- <u>Budget App</u> This is a web application where you can manage your budget: you have a list of transactions associated with a category so that you can see how much money you spend and on what.
   <u>Built with: PostgreSQL, Ruby On Rails, & BootStrap.</u>
- <u>Riyadh Season</u> This website gives users a little insight or an idea of how Saudi Arabia celebrates the Riyadh season annual festival, this year along with the previous one. In addition to, getting to know the people behind it. <u>Built with: JavaScript, HTML, CSS & BootStrap.</u>
- <u>Math Magicians</u> Math magicians is a website for all the math lovers out there. It's a Single Page App that allows users to make simple calculations and read math-related code. **Built with: React, React** testing library, CSS & Routing.

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

Feb 2022 - Present

- Mentored 10 junior web developers, providing detailed technical support through over 50 code reviews every month.
- Implemented strategies to help maintain motivation and promote longevity in the program, resulting in a 5% increase in program retention.
- Expanded my network and formed strong bonds with 6 out of 10 mentees.

## **EDUCATION**

MICROVERSE Jan 2022 - Present

# Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.